Guide to the Committee of University Development, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on University Development, Yale University, records
1939-1940
RU 435
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The records consist of materials documenting the planning needs of the Engineering School, Yale Law School Library, and School of Medicine.
Yale University. Committee on University Development
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of materials documenting the planning needs of the Engineering School, Yale Law School Library, and School of Medicine.
Campus planning; College facilities -- Planning; Educational planning; Universities and colleges -- Planning; Yale Law Library; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Planning; Yale University. Committee on University Development; Yale University. President's Office; Yale University. School of Engineering; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Committee on University Development Records, Accession 1940-A-008
  - Engineering School; 3 reports on needs of
    - "Engineers for Tomorrow", 1940 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A Proposal for the Increase of the Murray Guggenheim Fund in the Department of Metallurgy", 1940 January
    - "Opportunities and Needs in Metallurgy", 1940 June
  - Law Library [Fund]; 4 reports on needs of
    - "Needs of the Yale Law Library with respect to French Law Books", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Needs of the Yale Law Library with respect to Rumanian Law Books", undated
    - "Opportunity and Plan for Development in the Latin-American Field", undated
    - "Plan for Development in Criminal Law, Criminology, and Legal Medicine", 1940 May
  - Medical School; 4 reports on needs of
    - "Opportunities and Needs in Public Health", 1939 Jan, 1940 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "A Program of Research on Haemolytic Streptococci", 1939 April
    - "Proposal for a Demonstration Dental Clinic and Training Unit", 1939 June
  - Nutrition, Proposal for an Institute of, 1939 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Psychiatry at Yale, 1940 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Yale in Publication"
    - The Yale University Press and the Yale Review, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)